A student named Charles Meliton has compromising photographs of my friend.
Earth to Loki?
All the compromising photos and files are here.
I’m sorry for having you abducted.
So Loki was right. You're the mastermind.
More than half a year ago,
my brother investigated several cases
that connected all to one person only known as "M."
My classmate is missing.
- Just picking up the trash, ma'am. - Oh.
John Bautista?
You? You're the one who abducted them?
And now it’s your turn.
It's your turn.
I'm begging you, please...
Lorelei!
Looks like we need to teach that guy a lesson again.
Let’s see if he still won’t learn from this.
She's awake.
Is this the end for me?
I don’t want to die yet!
I want to achieve my dreams.
And make more friends.
I still want to get to know myself.
I still want to talk to my dad.
And I want to understand why, after you were gone,
he’s grown distant from me.
I want us to make things right.
But if this is what’s meant for me,
there’s nothing I can do.
No matter how I try to run,
it will always find me.
Is this really it?
Is there no one left to help me?
Oh, Loki…
Please…
help me.
Loki! Help!
Shadows
in the dark are crawling.
Keeping watch and barring your way.
As if the line could not be crossed.
To every scream and every tremor.
These walls remain the only witness.
Every noise is etched in here.
Like fire and ammunition for your memory.
Heed the warnings.
The threats poised to strike.
For this world
is not what you imagined.
Heed the warnings.
Open up your eyes.
For this world
is not what you imagined.
Heed the warnings.
So you’re awake, Lorelei.
Perfect timing.
You want to know what happened to those missing students, right?
I’ll let you know.
First, I killed them one by one.
One by one.
Then I melted them.
You know, I melted them, right?
But since you’re special…
I’ll melt you alive.
Hey, can you see this?
What? This is it. Are you ready, huh?
Are you ready?
This is it.
Such a bother.
Where were we?
This is it.
Shit!
Don’t cause trouble, okay? I’ll come back for you.
I'm just going to answer this, okay?
Don't make a sound! Come on!
Don't make a sound!
Don't! Don't! Don't!
Don't make a sound! Don't make a sound!
Please! Please! Please! Don't make a sound!
Don't make a sound! Shut up! Shut up! I'll kill you!
I'll kill you! Shut up! Damn it!
- Mom. - Hello?
- Yes, Mom? Sorry, I missed your call. Mom. - What are you doing? I’ve been calling.
- Mom? Hello? - You’re not answering your phone.
Sorry, I was in class, so I missed your call.
Are you going home this sembreak?
Your dad and aunt are asking me if you’re still alive.
What's going on with you?
- Just tell Auntie and Dad I can’t go home. - Where are you, really?
- Sorry, Mom. Hello? - Why won't you tell me?
- Alright. Alright, Mom. - What's that?
- Help! - Why so loud? Where are you? Son!
Son!
You... been at it for a while, huh?
Since earlier! Since earlier!
What's your problem? I was talking to my mom!
Shut up! You're so loud! You're so loud!
You’ve really been at it for a while, huh!
You’ve been at it since earlier. You’re so annoying.
What, huh?
You really want to die?
You're so annoying.
Come here.
- No. No. - Don't cause trouble. Don't cause trouble!
I admire your survival instincts, for a woman.
You’re so tiring! You’re so tiring!
Sorry, I need to put you back there.
I’m going to kill you!
No! Please!
No! No!
Please.
No!
Lorelei! Lorelei! Are you okay?
Lorelei.
Lorelei, are you okay?
Loki.
Loki!
I've been waiting so long for this, M.
- How did you know... - Quite clever...
I must say.
The way you managed to kidnap those victims
without anyone noticing and alerting the campus police.
How you handled those corpses,
letting the victim’s body melt inside the drum.
But it was very foolish how you disposed
the liquefied remains.
Just so you know,
sodium hydroxide creates a malodorous smell
when it melts a human body.
On the basement, by the anatomy room,
there’s always a foul smell.
Sometimes, I feel like there’s someone there.
Does it smell like something’s rotting?
No,
it’s like chemical.
It hurts my nose.
It’s giving me headache too.
Where’s Lori?
Where’s that foul smell coming from?
It’s near the anatomy room.
In the anatomy...
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
You know a lot!
Come, let me give you a refresher in chemistry.
Harder!
I must say…
I’m a little disappointed in you.
I thought you’d be smarter than the other criminals I’ve encountered.
Now, I have a question.
Are you regretting killing Rhea now?
Are you crazy?
Who are you talking about? Who’s Rhea?
You actually managed to laugh, huh!
Okay. Let’s do this the old way.
An eye for an eye,
and a tooth for a tooth.
You killed those other girls by melting their bodies.
I’ll do the same to you.
Wait, you’re wrong.
Who? M? I’m not M!
Who’s M?
Now you’re denying it.
I’m really not M!
If you hadn’t poisoned Genesis,
he definitely reported that you’re M.
I can’t do that!
Believe me, I didn’t kill him.
I’m really not M!
He knows you.
So you kept him quiet while the cops escorted him,
by using a succinylcholine syringe, right?
Right.
So you admit it?
You are M.
The M behind all these killings!
The M who killed Rhea!
Yes, okay?
Yes, I'm the one who killed Genesis and those three women.
But…
I don’t even know that Rhea!
And I’m not M!
I’m not M!
Liar. Don’t play with me!
I’m not M. I’m not M.
- I'm not lying. - Enough!
- I’m not lying! - Enough!
Why should I believe you, when everything you say is a lie!
This is for Mylene,
Michelle,
Madonna
and for Rhea.
See you in hell.
No. Loki, that’s enough!
- Let me go! Let me go! - That’s enough!
No.
Do you really think what you’re doing is right?
What the hell do I care?
This is on me. You don’t need to care about it!
Loki…
if you do that,
you’re no different from him.
You’re turning to a murderer just like him!
Besides,
we don’t have proof beyond reasonable doubt
that he's the one who killed Rhea.
Loki…
how do you think Rhea would feel
knowing you became the monster
that you once fought?
Do you think Rhea would want to know you killed that person
for her?
Loki…
this isn’t you.
Please…
think about this.
You’re right.
I’m not like him.
I don’t wanna be like him.
Your wrist only has minor abrasions from being tied up.
But other than that, you have no other injuries.
Are you okay?
Do you feel anything?
Nothing hurts on my body…
I’m not okay.
Here in the infirmary, we treat physical injuries.
But when you go through that kind of violence,
like what happened to you,
there’s mental and psychological damage.
Wait.
Just go to her office or give her a call, she can help.
Thank you, Nurse?
Melissa. Mel, for short.
Tip for you, when the bad memories come back,
take a deep breath in through your nose...
and slowly out through your mouth.
See?
Nice.
I sometimes think
that since students’ mental health isn’t being taken care of,
the killings on campus keep happening.
It’s sad, they’re so young.
Has it been like this at Clark U for a long time?
Honestly, it’s normal for students here to suddenly travel
or drop out mid-semester.
But since last year,
it’s been happening more often and it’s not normal anymore.
It’s possible they just dropped out, or fell victim to a crime.
I just don’t understand why the admin doesn’t seem to be doing anything.
Some parents are pulling their kids out because of what’s happening.
Okay, I’ll let you be for now.
How are you?
How's your fist?
It's nothing. Just a bit red.
Come here.
Maybe Nurse Mel is right.
The students' mental health gets neglected, so this is what happens.
We can’t blame it all on mental health.
Sometimes,
people are just pure evil.
Chief Estrada…
you have something for us?
Did John Bautista admit he's M?
No, he didn't. But...
this is the last part of John's confession that I think will lead us to M.
Watch this video of his interrogation.
Why won't you believe me, huh?
I really don't know him!
I only talked to him on the phone!
Only on the phone. I haven't even seen him!
Sometimes he sends people
but that's it.
I haven’t even seen him. Believe me!
Can you describe his voice?
Just…
cold and deep.
The kind that gives you chills when you hear it.
Hasn’t any of his people mentioned his name?
None at all! I’ve been telling you this, haven’t I?
None.
I only know him as M.
That's it.
But…
But he has people.
He has people.
He’s called by another name.
What was it again…
John?
John? John!
Call an ambulance!
Chief, I heard John say in the video that he was talking to someone.
I can verify that information to be true,
because while I was in the drum,
I heard him talking to someone on the phone.
He was talking to someone before his mom.
He called someone?
Chief, didn’t you get John’s phone?
To trace who he was last talking to earlier.
We got his phone, but it’s already damaged.
Chemicals spilled on it. It's corroded, so we can't use it as evidence.
Loki.
He’s everywhere, Lorelei.
He’s got eyes and ears everywhere.
Wait…
John's mouth is still moving in the video.
Looks like he’s trying to say something.
Moria... Moriarty.
Moriarty?
Moriarty!
Moria...
Moriarty.
Moria... Moriarty!
Moria...
Moriarty.
Moria.
I heard a scream in your room.
I thought you were having nightmares.
Don’t worry.
It’s normal, especially for those who’ve gone through near-death experience.
Yeah, right.
I’m having nightmares from you replaying John’s video over and over.
I thought you were doing some kind of ritual.
Have you ever actually slept?
Don’t tell me…
you worked on this all night.
Do you know them?
I don’t think so.
But, wait…
that guy looks familiar.
I feel like I’ve watched him in a series before.
Why do you ask?
They're actors who played Moriarty
in the modern adaptations of Sherlock Holmes.
And James Moriarty
is considered as the arch-nemesis of Sherlock.
Moriarty is a professor of Mathematics,
known as "the Napoleon of crime.”
The mastermind behind half of the evil in the world.
So you’re saying…
Moriarty is just the codename of the person you’re after?
Exactly.
How dare he use the name of my most favorite
antagonist.
But why is he killing?
What wrong did they do to him?
The victims didn't do anything to make Moriarty want to kill them.
Well, except for Janine.
Her case is separate from Moriarty’s.
And it’s clear that Janine’s case is a crime of passion.
But for the rest…
they’re all connected.
Perhaps, Moriarty...
like in the novel,
this is playing wilth Holmes,
and I am his Holmes.
Wait.
Like what I’ve said before,
sometimes,
people are just pure evil.
I just remembered…
someone called John
while I was in the drum.
Though, it’s kind of baffling, but…
I heard him tell the other person they’ll teach you a lesson.
You think he was speaking to Moriarty at that time?
I wasn’t there.
I can’t say.
But it's possible.
Since, Moriarty ordered all of that.
And I just feel strange about this case.
Strange?
Yeah.
Now we know someone’s working for Moriarty.
It’s possible someone’s inside the campus police.
And that explains why the phone was destroyed.
And that explains why John was poisoned
while in police custody.
Alright, I’m going back to sleep.
Good night.
By the way, Lorelei.
I have a request,
I just want you to keep an eye out of anything suspicious.
And stay vigilant.
Especially when you’re alone.
I hope this doesn’t happen to you again.
It’s sad to think that all we can do for those who passed
is to remember them
and fight for their justice.
But they won’t remember it anymore,
because they’re gone.
This isn’t for those who are gone.
This is for those left behind.
Maybe this was the only way they could think of,
to show their love for their dead loved ones.
Why are all your exam scores zero?
Are you disappointed because I got so many zeros on the exam?
I’m not disappointed.
I just can’t believe that you’ve got zeroes.
I mean, with how smart you are,
you didn’t answer a single one?
Honestly,
I’m not like everyone else who’s obsessed with grades and awards.
I refuse to be enslaved by numbers.
Those medals and certificates
don’t mean anything to me.
Aren’t you worried you might fail?
Enrolling again would cost so much.
And on top of that, you’ll be delayed graduating.
Right now…
that’s the least of my priorities.
What matters to me
is this club.
I know you have responsibilities in this club and to our fellow students.
But let me remind you, Loki,
at the end of the day, we’re still students.
And our top priority is still to graduate.
We need to be equipped with the proper skills and knowledge,
for anything we choose to do in the real world.
Fine, whatever.
Sorry to bother you, can I come in?
Yes. Of course. Come in.
- Okay, have a seat. - Wow.
Your room is really nice.
You dropped by, what’s up?
I’d like to get your opinion.
I’m speaking on behalf of the Paranormal Club.
We have a ghost hunting activity
at the abandoned school building.
We’ve been going back and forth for five days,
but still haven’t seen anything.
But this last time…
we caught something.
Here. Watch this, watch this. Here.
- Loki! Come on, let’s watch. - Here, here.
Wait. Here.
Guys, we’re on the 2nd floor.
So far, we haven’t seen any ghosts.
Looks like there’s really nothing.
Seems like the person who told us was spreading fake news.
- What a waste of time. - Yeah, right.
Shit, did you hear that?
Right? Did you hear that?
- Did you hear that? - Hey.
Hey.
Yeah!
- It's not a good joke! - No, it's true!
- Hey! Don’t mess with us! - Stay quiet!
Guys, this might be real, there’s a ghost here.
Oh, there!
Listen, there’s something.
Hey, shit. Andrew peed himself!
- Did you pee yourself? - No way! No way!
- Andrew, you peed. - You're gross. You're gross.
- No, it just got wet. - You're gross. You're gross.
I told you! There. Did you hear that?
So clear. Did you hear that?
Right?
Since when do we even solve paranormal stuff?
Come on, Loki. Rosetta’s asking for our help.
But paranormal cases are the turf of the Paranormal Club.
They’re the ones who should investigate supernatural phenomena,
whether it’s real or not.
We at the Q.E.D. Club rely solely on facts and evidences.
Loki!
What? I’m stating facts.
Do you give your word, Loki?
And that question is relevant because?
You told me when we met at the White Hostel
that you’d do me a big favor…
if I post your photos on CU Confessions while you’re investigating.
I even promoted Lori’s blog
so more people can read about your solved cases.
I don’t usually owe a favor to anyone.
But we may owe you one, if you do exactly what you’ve said.
Any kind of help
would be a big deal to get our club noticed.
Sure!
My pleasure!
I’ll call it quits if you help us figure out that mysterious sound.
Yes, Rosseta, good thing,
Loki here is such an honorable man, and he honors his every word.
So you can count on us to help.
Yay! Okay.
So see you at the abandoned school building, okay?
I’ll just send you the address.
Don’t ghost us, okay?
Nothing. Bye. Thank you.
I wish someone would walk in and ask us to solve a far more engaging case.
Professor Morayta!
Lorelei.
- Oh, you’re a member here? - Yes.
As a journ student, you like solving problems.
Did you just pass by?
Yes, since your club is good at solving problems, I came here.
Oh, well. Thank you, sir.
Oh, by the way, this is Loki Mendez, our club president.
Loki, this is Professor Morayta, our Math 100 teacher.
Loki?
Like the Norse trickster god?
Mm-hmm.
I’ve heard so much about your club and it’s a pleasure to finally meet you.
So, Prof, did you witness a murder?
Or find a decomposing corpse?
Either way,
we’re obliged to assist.
At least it's way better than chasing a nonexistent ghost.
Right?
I didn’t want to make a big deal out of it,
so I didn’t go to campus police.
No one died or got hurt,
thankfully.
I have a student,
Stein Alberts, 3rd year BS Math.
Today’s our screening to become Clark U’s representative.
Master Math is next month.
It’s an intercollegiate math competition where Stein’s a topnotcher.
Actually, he’s really good.
But...
he didn’t go to class.
We tried calling and texting him,
even on all his social media, but nothing got a seen mark.
When did anyone last see him?
His classmates said they saw him around 4 p.m. at the library,
to do research.
But that’s unlikely, since Stein doesn’t need to review.
Later that night, he did not come home to his dorm.
His dormmates said they thought he slept over at a classmate’s place.
Prof, if Stein didn’t make it through the screening,
who’s the 3rd year’s representative?
Monica Segundo.
She’s second in their block.
But Stein always ends up on top.
I know Monica has wanted to join the math competition for a long time.
But since Stein’s out,
she’s next in line.
Excuse me, ma’am.
I just want to ask,
did you see this man yesterday, around 4 p.m.?
Yes, I saw him. He even left his bag here.
He was in a hurry. Maybe around 4:30?
He just left his bag?
This is his bag. You can return it to him.
Okay. Thank you.
Look what I’ve found.
What is that?
That rugged bag does not suit you.
This is Stein’s bag.
I asked around at the library.
Didn’t Professor Morayta say someone saw him there yesterday?
Well, the librarian said he left this bag and didn’t come back.
So my guess is there might be a clue here about his whereabouts.
That’s her, Stein’s blockmate,
or so-called rival.
Hi! Excuse me.
Are you Stein Alberts’ blockmate?
That weirdo,
he didn’t go to class today.
He probably chickened out,
so he decided not to show up for the screening.
You’re Monica Segundo,
the eternal number two of your class, right?
Yeah. I don’t know you.
Congratulations, by the way.
You’ve been chosen as your batch representative
in math quiz bee.
You’re lucky your toughest rival didn’t show up on your screening day.
What a coincidence.
I have no idea what you’re talking about!
Do you think she has something to do with Stein’s disappearance?
She’s defensive.
She’s the primary suspect.
Thank you.
So I talked to two of Stein’s friends in the Math Club.
- He has friends? - Mm-hmm.
Well, apparently,
the two I talked to both claimed to be his friends.
They got along since, well, Stein’s a bit of a weirdo.
He’s apparently really smart,
that’s why only a few can relate to them.
But...
they did mention something really interesting,
that I think is worth noting.
They said,
when they talk, they speak in codes.
What sort of codes?
Sometimes it’s a series of numbers.
But usually, it’s Morse code, dots and dashes.
And I quote,
"If our phone gets stolen,
someone gossiping might read our conversation.
When we talk in codes, they can’t understand."
Interesting.
I wonder what they’re talking about?
Why does it have to be encrypted?
Is it really that confidential?
It’s probably their protection,
from the likes of Chad Ellison.
I get him.
Chad Ellison?
You mean Charles Meliton?
Yeah, whatever. That one.
Oh, Loki...
But,
if they’re hiding something like that,
it means there’s something they really don’t want the public to know.
Everybody has a secret, Lorelei.
The victim is probably the kind of person
who doesn’t like to share anything about their private life.
Do you think Moriarty has something to do with this?
I don’t know.
Maybe he’s gotten bored.
Come in!
Oh, Professor Morayta!
Sorry to bother you.
Good news, Stein just texted,
he said not to worry.
He just had to attend to an emergency, so he didn’t go to school.
Sorry if I bothered you earlier,
but, still, thank you very much.
I should have waited for his reply.
No problem, sir.
See you in class.
- See you. - Loki.
Well, I guess that’s a case closed.
For now.
- He's taking forever, Rosetta. - He's taking so long.
- He'll come. He'll come. - I’ve been waiting so long.
Maybe he got scared.
- No. He'll come. There! They're here! - Hello, Rosetta!
- There! There it is! There! - Alright.
Rosetta, sorry, we're late.
We thought you weren’t coming.
Didn’t your last class end early?
It’s because of Loki. His class ended late, so I had to wait.
- What the... - Oh, okay. It’s fine! Come on!
They’re just scared. They don’t want to come.
Here, grab it.
- That’s it! - Let's go?
- Let's go! Game! - Alright!
- Game? Game! - Let's go. Okay.
- Let's go. I'll go first. - Over there.
- Come on, let’s go! - You go first!
- Alright! - Alright!
Guys, we’re coming in. We’re at the abandoned building.
I’m freaked out. Here they are.
This is my squad.
- Guys, smile at the camera. Let's go. - It's so dark here.
Wait, wait, Rosetta!
Let’s do a sandwich formation.
I’ll go first,
you’re behind me, and the other two take the back.
To keep our guests safe.
We don’t know,
one of them might pee from fear.
So loud! Go ahead, you first!
Andrew, right?
I heard you wet your pants the last time you were here.
You know, you’re spreading fake news.
It was just water that spilled on me.
Game. Let’s get serious.
- This place is crazy, guys! - Wild!
So creepy in here.
- Let’s go over there. - It's so messy.
Maybe it's here.
Wait.
I think there's something in the hole.
Hold on, let me check.
Wait, wait, wait! What are you gonna do?
- I’m just checking. - You might get hurt later.
No, I’ll just check. There’s something.
Wait.
Andrew!
No, just stay there. I’ll just check.
- If we get haunted... - Andrew, come on! You might get hurt!
- No, I’ll just check. Stay right there. - Don’t do it.
What's gotten into Andrew?
- Don't do it. - Andrew!
Hey!
- Andrew! - Andrew!
I'll just check. Wait.
I'm getting scared.
Oh, there! There!
Andrew! What's going on with you?
- Andrew! - Help me!
Help me! Hurry! Help me!
- Come on! - Help me!
- Loki! Help them! - Help me!
- Hey! Guys, come on! - So here we go. Let's follow Loki.
- Oh, no. We're doomed. - Hurry!
Help! Help!
- Help! - Come on!
- I'm getting scared! - Please!
- Help me! - Come on!
Help me! Come on!
Hurry! What, guys?
What was that?
- I'm not doing this! - Did you see that?
Someone just went through there!
Did you see that?
I told you! I don’t want to be here anymore!
The next time you attempt to fool us,
make sure it works.
He's such a killjoy.
Oh, come on! You’re so hard to please!
You’re so corny, dude!
Exactly.
Come on. That's so corny.
If that touches you...
- I’ll go first. - You go first, Andrew.
Let’s go, guys!
You're the sacrifice.
Guys, this place is super creepy.
But I really have no idea what that jerk is saying.
This place is really creepy.
I've already made my assessment that ghosts don’t ex...
- Hey, come here. - So, guys.
We’re now on the 2nd floor, where we heard the knocking and rustling.
So now we're just waiting...
- Hey. - It's so dark.
- There! - Hey!
Did you hear that? Did you hear that?
- Did you hear that? - Yes, I heard that.
Loki, how about you?
You said that there were three knocks
before the scratches.
All I heard were the knocks.
Maybe...
maybe it can't decide.
That could still change. Who knows?
Maybe it's indecisive.
Right?
There it is, guys.
We’ll finally see what we’re looking for.
Look.
It’s like… the painting is moving.
Oh, jeez!
That's true!
Just kidding!
I just feel like the background music fits.
- He'll get karma. - That fast?
Hey, wait.
What's that?
I don't want anymore! I don't want anymore!
Someone's inside!
This place has a rodent problem,
but as you can see...
no ghosts.
No, no. There's really something.
Promise. Let's try upstairs. Promise.
- Come on. Come on. - One more chance.
- Promise, there's something. - Let's go upstairs.
- Let's go. Don't be scared. - Come on, let's go.
- Let's go upstairs. - Let's go.
- There we go! Let's go! - Come on.
- Come on! Come on! - I'll be your camera man for now.
Oh, did you hear that?
- Huh? There's nothing. - I told you it's true.
That’s what we heard last time we came here.
Yeah, this is the place.
Hey! Whoever you are, show yourself!
- Who are you talking to? - Hey, bro. Don't be like that!
You want me to get you possessed?
Oh, why me?
Is anyone here?
If you can’t speak...
answer in the way that you know.
- Hey, Loki! - Hey, what are you doing?
Communicating.
To ghosts?
- Now you believe. - You’re a believer now?
I'm so proud. I'm really proud. I'm gonna cry.
As I’ve said before,
ghosts don’t exist.
You’re trying to communicate, aren’t you?
We were here when we heard the rustling, right?
There!
The ghost might be here, guys.
I don’t know.
- Maybe there really is something. - What are these guys doing?
- Why did they stop? - Let's just try.
- Loki can handle it. - Loki, huh.
I knew it!
Knocks and scratches,
dots and dashes.
Are you rapping?
- What are you saying? - What was that?
- Just go ahead. - Okay, I’ll come.
- You go first! Come on. - Let's go.
Why are we here?
What's going on?
You still don’t get it, Lorelei.
- Someone answered, "Yes." - Huh?
I didn’t hear anyone answer "Yes."
- Just some rustling. - I’ll explain later.
Let's find him first.
Who?
If you can hear me,
knock.
So we know where you are.
What's that?
Where's that?
What’s that? Where’s it coming from?
- Over there? - Yeah.
Guys, it's so creepy.
Hey, don't open it. Loki!
Here we go, here we go.
Stand next to me.
Ouch!
- What's your problem? - Hey.
What are you gonna do with that, Loki? Loki!
- What's that? What are you doing? - What's that?
Hey.
Shoot.
Was he possessed?
Hey.
Man, are you okay?
Man!
What happened?
Hey, are you okay?
- Wake up! Wake up! - Hey, wake up!
Exactly, that’s why you’re looking pale.
- Be careful. - Let's just pray.
You're next.
Foul! No way, bro.
- Let me copy, okay? - You're next.
I wish it was always like this.
Before the tragedy occurs, we can stop it and save even more people.
I wish.
But that’s not always the case.
I know that.
I just want to savor this feeling.
It feels so good to be able to save a life.
Wait, before we go home,
can you explain to me how you knew it was Stein Alberts and not a ghost?
Do you remember Stein’s two nerdy friends you talked to yesterday?
Mm-hmm.
Stein communicates with them through codes,
sometimes dots,
sometimes dashes.
It’s Morse code.
A sequence of short and long signals called dots and dashes
where every dot, dash, or sequence of the two
represents a letter.
There!
Did you hear that? Did you hear that?
You said that they were three knocks before the scratches.
All I heard were the knocks.
I noticed the knocking and rustling patterns
in the video are consistent
and in the abandoned building.
So I thought they meant something.
I think Stein was trying to communicate with the paranormal believers yesterday.
By sending a series of knocks and scratches.
Where every knock is a dot,
while every scratch is a dash.
If you convert the signals to Morse code,
three dots,
three dashes,
and another three dots,
it's S-O-S.
In other words,
a distress signal.
Is anyone here?
When I asked if anyone was there...
If you can speak...
It answered three scratches.
But twice
which means two pairs of three dashes is equivalent to...
"Yes."
That means someone really needs our help.
So what about the message Professor Morayta received?
If it wasn’t from Stein, who was it from?
It’s probably the person behind Stein’s kidnapping.
He sent a message to stop us from looking for Stein.
Let’s be honest...
we both know who’s behind this incident.
This case stands apart from the ones that came before it.
This time, we weren’t investigating a murder
to find out who's the murderer.
Instead, we managed to save a life before tragedy could strike.
The victim, Stein Alberts,
is known in school as a math wizard
who effortlessly and consistently represents his school in math contests.
He had no idea that his talent had sparked resentment in someone else.
Despite his unassuming nature, he still became a victim of violence.
In the process of gathering evidence,
something unexpected happened,
the person behind Stein’s abduction confessed.
The culprit turned out to be Monica Segundo,
Stein’s academic rival.
Someone texted me, saying they could grant a wish for 3,000.
Back then, I wished Stein would disappear.
So I'd be Clark U's Math representative.
I admit I did it, but I never meant for Stein to get hurt.
Imagine, a person’s life valued at only 3,000 pesos.
It’s heartbreaking to hear such stories,
and even more painful to know
that someone could act like a genie granting wishes,
only to exploit another’s emotions.
And yet, even with the relief of saving a life,
there remains an uneasy feeling,
as if every case, no matter how different,
keeps pulling us back toward one name.
One shadow that looms over it all...
M.
I want to join the Q.E.D. Club!
We don’t take just anyone as a club member.
Catherine Del Rosario.
But we might not need your help anymore
since this is being treated as a suspected suicide.
What's this?
Just open it and see for yourself.
A ballpen?
Daniel Geronimo.
Justin Ruiz is my friend, the guy who jumped.
I need your help.
One of our Photography Club members, I found her bleeding in our clubroom.
Let the game begin!